A Finding Aid to the Eugenie Gershoy Papers, 1914-1983, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
Eugenie Gershoy papers
1914-1983
Archives of American Art
Gershoy, Eugenie, 1901?-1983 or 6
AAA.gerseuge
Archival Resource Key
7.2 Linear feet
The papers of sculptor and art instructor, Eugenie Gershoy, measure 7.2 linear feet and date from 1914 to 1983. The collection documents Gershoy's career through biographical material, correspondence, business records, notes, writings, artwork, printed material, and photographs.
Biographical Note
Born in Krivoi Rog, Russia on January 1, 1901, Eugenie was the youngest of the Gershoy children. The family immigrated to New York City in 1903. She later became a U.S. citizen.
With the aid of two scholarships, she attended the Art Students League and studied under A. Stirling Calder, Leo Lentelli, Kenneth Hayes Miller, Boardman Robinson, and Carl Walters. During the late 1920s and early 1930s, she maintained a studio with Harry Gottlieb in Woodstock, New York. From 1936 to 1939, under the WPA Federal Art Project, she worked in conjunction with Max Spivak on murals for the children's recreation room in the Astoria branch of the Queens Borough Public Library, New York.
Gershoy's first solo show was at the Robinson Gallery in New York in 1940. Following a year of teaching at the New Orleans Art School, she moved to San Francisco in 1942. In 1946 she taught ceramics at the California School of Fine Arts, and in May 1950, she studied at Yaddo.
In addition to visits to England and France in the early 1930s, Gershoy travelled to Mexico and Guatemala in 1947, 1948, and 1961. She worked in Paris in 1951 and toured Africa, India, and the Orient in 1955.
Eugenie Gershoy died in 1986.
Scope and Content Note
The Eugenie Gershoy papers date from 1914 to 1983, measure 7.2 linear feet, and reflect Gershoy's career as a sculptor and teacher. The collection contains biographical material, correspondence, business records, notes, writings, artwork of Gershoy and others, printed material including exhibition catalogs, and photographs with subjects including Gershoy, her friends and colleagues, her studio, and her artwork.
Correspondence forms the bulk of the collection and includes correspondence between Gershoy and her siblings and their families regarding her activities, as well as with colleagues, many of whom were associated with the Woodstock Artist Association, and many of whom were museum colleagues.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into eight series according to material type. The contents of each series have been arranged chronologically.
Missing Title
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1939-1971 (boxes 1, 8-9; 3 folders)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1914-1983, undated (boxes 1-6, 8-9; 5.8 linear ft.)
Series 3: Business Records, 1952-1978 (box 6; 5 folders)
Series 4: Notes, 1967-1970, undated (box 6; 3 folders)
Series 5: Writings, 1970, undated (box 6; 2 folders)
Series 6: Artwork, 1932-1978, undated (boxes 6, 8-9, OV 10, 26 folders)
Series 7: Printed Material, 1932-1983, undated (boxes 7, 9; 19 folders)
Series 8: Photographs, 1916-1983, undated (boxes 7, 9; 12 folders)
Related Material
Related material in the Archives of American Art includes a transcribed oral history interview with Eugenie Gershoy conducted by Mary McChesney for the Archives of American Art's New Deal and the Arts Oral History Program, October 15, 1964. A link to the transcript is provided from the online catalog.
Provenance
The Eugenie Gershoy papers were donated to the Archives of American Art between 1975 and 1983 by the artist.
Restrictions on Access
The collection is open for research. Patrons must use microfilm copy.
Alternative Forms Available
The collection is available on 35 mm microfilm reels 293, and 4966-4972 at Archives of American Art offices, and through interlibrary loan. Researchers should note that the arrangement of the material described in the container inventory does not reflect the arrangement of the collection on microfilm.
Painters -- New York (State) -- New York; Sculptors -- New York (State) -- New York; Draftsmen (artists) -- New York (State) -- New York; Ceramicists -- New York (State) -- New York; New Deal, 1933-1939; Federal aid to the arts; Sculpture, Modern -- 20th century -- New York (State) -- New York; Women artists; Women painters; Women ceramicists; Women sculptors; Prints; Christmas cards; Sketchbooks; Sketches; Photographs; Woodstock (N.Y.); Artists' studios -- New York (State); Nakian, Reuben, 1897-1986; Picken, George, 1898-; Pollet, Joseph C., 1897-1979; Presser, Josef, 1906-1967; Hart, Agnes, 1912-1979; Knight, Frederic C., 1898-1979; Marantz, Irving, 1912-1972; Millay, Edna St. Vincent, 1892-1950; Thomson, Virgil, 1896-; Varda, Jean; Woodstock Artists Association (Woodstock, N.Y.); Yaddo (Artist's colony); Refregier, Anton, 1905-; Scaravaglione, Concetta, 1900-1975; Soyer, Moses, 1899-1974; Soyer, Raphael, 1899-1987; Baker, Mildred, 1905-; Blanch, Lucile, 1895-1981; Blanch, Arnold, 1896-1968; Force, Juliana, 1876-1948; Federal Art Project (N.Y.); Gottlieb, Harry, 1895-; Fruhauf, Aline, 1909-1978; Calder, Alexander Stirling, 1870-1945; Breeskin, Adelyn Dohme, 1896-1986; Dehn, Virginia; Art Students League (New York, N.Y.)
- Biographical Material, 1939-1970; Series 1; Archival Resource Key; 3 Folders Boxes 1, 8-9
  Scope and Contents note
  Biographical material includes a résumé, membership cards, award certificates, and a biographical sketch. See also sol 8 for oversized biographical material.
  Existence and Location of Copies
  Biographical materials are on reel 293.
  - Biographical material, 1939-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Biographical material (see also box 8), 1965-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Oversized Biographical material, Certificate from Box 9, 1965-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1914-1983, undated; Series 2; Archival Resource Key; 5.8 Linear feet Boxes 1-6, 8-9
  Correspondence is primarily between Gershoy and family members and colleagues. Correspondence with her sister and brothers and their families discusses Gershoy's activities, including her relationships with Harry Gottlieb and Juliana Force. Correspondence with colleagues includes letters from Elizabeth Ames of Yaddo, Mildred Baker, Arnold and Lucile Blanch, Virginia Dehn, Aline Fruhauf, Agnes Hart, Frederic Knight, Josef Presser, and Virgil Thomson. There are Christmas cards from Irving Marantz, George Picken, Anton Refregier, Moses Soyer, and Raphael Soyer. Correspondence found in box 9 is primarily from museum colleagues including Alfred Barr, Adelyn Breeskin, Juliana Force, and A. Hyatt Mayor. There is also a recommendation from Anton Refregier.
  See Appendix for a list of notable correspondents from Series 2.
  Appendix: List of Notable Correspondents from Series 2
  Art Students League: see Photographs
  Avery, Frances: undated Christmas cards (2); 1967 Christmas card
  Baber, Alice: Oct 16, 1975; Oct 21, 1975
  Baker, Mildred: undated letters (20); May 22, 1969; [Aug 1971]; May 25, 1980; Mar 10, 1981; Mar 17, 1981; Mar 26, 1981; Jun 5, 1981; 1981 Christmas card; 1982 Christmas card
  Bertoia, Harry: see Printed Material for autographed exhibition announcement
  Blanch, Arnold and Lucile: undated letters (2); Jan 1975; Dec 18, 1975; 1977 Christmas card; Jan 1977; Jan 1978; also see Printed Material for exhibition announcements and catalogs; also see Photographs
  Botkin, Henry and Rhoada: undated cards (5); 1973 Christmas card; Jul 29, 1974; Aug 15, 1975; 1975 Christmas card; 1976 Christmas card; 1977 Christmas card; also see Printed Material for an exhibition announcement
  Breeskin, Adelyn: May 23, 1969; Dec 19, 1969; Feb 17, 1970; Nov 24, 1970; Jan 14, 1971; Feb 22, 1971; Jul 14, 1971; Sep 13, 1971; Dec 22, 1971; Feb 8, 1972; Mar 30, 1972; May 30, 1972; May 16, 1975; Oct 29, 1975; Nov 21, 1975
  Cadmus, Paul: Oct 18, 1956 postcard
  Calder, A. Stirling: see Photographs
  Castellon, Rolando: undated letter; [Apr 1968]; May 13, 1968; Jan 6, 1972; Apr 5, 1979
  Chase, Doris: undated letter
  De Creeft, Jose: see Printed Material for an exhibition catalog
  Dehn, Virginia (Mrs. Adolph Dehn): undated Christmas card; Dec 9, 1975; [Jan 1976]; Dec 18, 1977; Feb 17, 1978; Dec 16, 1978; Dec 5, 1980; 1981 Christmas card; 1982 Christmas card; also see Printed Material for exhibition announcements and catalogs
  Dixon, Constance ("Consie," daughter of painter of the West, Maynard Dixon): 1949 Christmas card; May 5, 1952; 1961 Christmas card
  Engelking, Roberto (architect): undated letter; Jan 16, 1949; Mar 22, 1949
  Evergood, Philip: see Printed Material for an exhibition catalog
  Ferber, Herbert: see Printed Material for an exhibition catalog
  Force, Juliana: [mentioned in Oct 16, 1929, Apr 1930, April 29, 1930, Oct 1, 1930, Oct 25, 1930, Nov 1, 1930, Sep 12, 1932, and Sep 20, 1932 postcards]
  Fortess, Karl and Lillian: 1977 Christmas card; Aug 14, 1979; Dec 3, 1979; Jan 8, 1980; 1980 Christmas card; 1981 Christmas card; 1982 Christmas card
  Freilich, Michael: undated letter; also see Printed Material for exhibition announcement; also see Photographs
  Fruhauf [Vollmer], Aline: undated letters (22); Mar 31, 1944; Jan 3, 1948 (note from Susie Vollmer); Jan 18, 1950; Jan 27, 1950; Apr 15, 1950; Sep 9, 1957; Nov 29, 1957; Jan 15, 1958; Nov 1, 1958; Feb 1, 1961; Dec 21, 1970; Apr 14, 1972; Jan 15, 1974; Jun 12, 1974; Jun 18, 1975; Jun 3, 1977; Oct 23, 1977; 1977 Christmas card; Mar 11, 1978; Jul 18, 1979 (letter from Erwin Vollmer); 1980 Christmas card (from Erwin Vollmer)
  Gikow, Ruth: see Printed Material for exhibition announcements
  Glassgold, Adolph Cook (painter, former Whitney Museum curator): undated letter; May 26, 1948; 1972 Christmas card; 1977 Christmas card; 1978 New Year's card
  Gottlieb, Harry: [postcards dated 1923-1934 mention Gottlieb]; undated letter; Apr 27, 1977; also see Printed Material for an exhibition catalog; also see Photographs
  Goulet, Lorrie: see Printed Material for exhibition announcements
  Hardy, Marcella (writer from India): May 18, 1956
  Hart, Agnes: see Presser, Agnes Hart
  Hartwig, Cleo: see Printed Material for an exhibition announcement
  Howland, Isabella: undated letter; Sep 19, 1951; 1966 Christmas card; 1967 Christmas card; Jul 17, 1969; Jul 1971; 1971 Christmas card
  Klitgaard, Georgina: 1972 Christmas card
  Knight, Frederic and Dorothy: undated letters (6); May 19, 1953
  Knight, Frederic and Hortense: undated letters (3); Dec 5, 1975; 1977 Christmas card; Nov 18, 1978; Sep 16, 1979; Dec 7, 1980; Nov 23, 1981; also see Printed Material for exhibition announcements and catalogs
  Kosloff, Alexis (Russian dancer): [mentioned in Jul 5, 1928 postcard]
  Lonergan, Joy (Mrs. John Lonergan): undated letter; Jul 25, 1975; Jul 19, 1977; Apr 27, 1978; Mar 7, 1979; May 25, 1979; Sep 12, 1979; 1981 Christmas card
  Marantz, Irving and Evelyn: undated Christmas card; 1971 Christmas card; Jun 4, 1975; 1975 Christmas card; [Sep 5, 1978]; also see Printed Material for an exhibition catalog
  Mayer, Ralph and Bena: undated letters (3); Feb 10, 1975; Nov 29, 1977; May 16, 1980; Jan 1, 1981; Aug 7, 1981; 1981 Christmas card
  Nakian, Reuben: see Photographs
  O'Connor, Francis V.: undated letters (2); Jun 19, 1970; Nov 11, 1970; Dec 22, 1975
  Olds, Elizabeth: undated card
  Picken, George and Viola: undated letters (3); 1944 Christmas card; 1972 Christmas card; 1974 Christmas card; 1977 Christmas card; also see Printed Material for an exhibition catalog
  Pollet, Joseph: see Printed Material for an exhibition catalog; also see Photographs
  Presser, Josef and Agnes Hart: undated letters (3); [Sep 1970]; Nov 6, 1973; Feb 25, 1978; Feb 14, 1979; Feb 21, 1979; Mar 4, 1979; Mar 19, 1979; Jun 13, 1979; Sep 7, 1979; [Nov 4, 1979]; also see Printed Material for exhibition announcements and catalogs
  Reeves, Ruth: undated letter
  Refregier, Anton: 1971 Christmas card; 1973 Christmas card
  Robinson, Gertrude (author of The Cardinal, wife of Morton Robinson, novelist and poet): undated letter; Feb 6, 1972; 1974 Christmas card; 1977 Christmas card; Feb 16, 1978; Jun 20, 1978; 1978 Christmas card; Jun 20, 1978; Apr 17, 1979; Sep 10, 1979; Dec 19, 1980; Sep 22, 1981; Oct 17, 1981; Nov 12, 1981
  Rockwood, Paul and Alice (painter and Bishop Museum Director): undated letter; Dec 8, 1951; Jan 7, 1960
  Rogers, Jane C. (painter, sister of Leon Kroll): undated Christmas card; Dec 30, 1948
  Rose, Phyllis (writer): un Christmas card; Jan 23, 1977; Jul 1978; Dec 1981
  Sarg, Tony: [mentioned in Oct 30, 1923 and Nov 7, 1923 postcards]
  Scaravaglione, Concetta: Dec 22, 1959; Jun 24, 1960; also see Photographs
  Shibley, Gertrude (Painter): 1977 Christmas card; Jun 5, 1979
  Smith, Gretchen and Mary (daughters of Judson Smith): [Judson Smith mentioned in Feb 17, 1925 postcard]; undated Christmas cards (3); 1977 Christmas card; Sep 16, 1980; see Printed Material for an exhibition catalog for Judson Smith
  Soyer, David (son of Moses Soyer): 1977 Christmas card
  Soyer, Moses: undated Christmas card
  Soyer, Raphael: undated Christmas cards (3); 1980 Christmas card; 1981 Christmas card; 1982 Christmas card; also see Printed Material for exhibition announcements
  Still, James (Writer): Nov 8, 1950; Jun 8, 1979
  Striebel, Fritzi (Mrs. John Striebel, ceramic sculptor, writer): undated letters (11); Jun 6, 1975; Oct 14, 1975; Feb 1, 1976; [May 1976]; Aug 21, 1976; 1976 Christmas card; 1977 Christmas card; Feb 17, 1979; Apr 11, 1979; Jul 3, 1979; Oct 22, 1979; Nov 6, 1979; Nov 20, 1979; [1979 Christmas card]; Apr 5, 1980; Oct 5, 1980; Dec 30, 1980; Jan 9, 1981; Apr 22, 1981; May 12, 1981; Oct 22, 1981; Nov 16, 1981; 1981 Christmas card; 1982 Christmas card; Feb 26, 1983; [Mar 1983]
  Taylor, Joshua: Dec 20, 1972; Dec 5, 1975
  Thomson, Virgil (composer): undated letters (2); Apr 1, 1970; Jun 8, 1971; Nov 8, 1971; Jan 1, 1972
  Van Veen, Stuyvesant: undated letter; Nov 23, 1976
  Varda, Jean: see Photographs
  Varian, Dorothy: undated letters (5); Jul 17, 1977; Mar 30, 1981
  Vollmer, Aline Fruhauf: see Fruhauf
  Whitney Studio Club: [mentioned in Jan 31, 1928, Apr 9, 1928, and Feb 16, 1929 postcards]
  Wilder, Thornton: Jul 20, 1953
  Wright, Russell (industrial designer): undated Christmas cards (5); Dec 12, 1972; Feb 2, 1976
  Yaddo: undated letters (4): Oct 17, 1949; Dec 12, 1949; Jan 9, 1950; Jan 24, 1950; Mar 31, 1950; Aug 23, 1950; Aug 24, 1950; Oct 9, 1950; Oct 11, 1950; Feb 26, 1951; also see Photographs
  Zorach, Tessim: May 11, 1968; Nov 20, 1970; Nov 28, 1970
  - Correspondence, first names only, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 2-5)
    Scope and Contents
    Reel 4966
  - Correspondence, 1914-1937, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 1, Folder 6-46)
  - Correspondence, 1942-1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
  - Correspondence, 1946-Mar., 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 3-47)
    Reel 4967
  - Correspondence, Apr.-Dec., 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 2, Folder 48-53)
    Reel 4968
  - Correspondence, 1960-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 1-48)
  - Correspondence, Jan.-Nov., 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 3, Folder 49-55)
    Reel 4969
  - Correspondence, Dec., 1971-Sept., 1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 1-29)
  - Correspondence, Oct., 1974-Feb., 1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 4, Folder 30-53)
    Reel 4970
  - Correspondence (see also box 8), Mar., 1976-Feb., 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 1-31)
  - Correspondence, Mar., 1978-Apr., 1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 5, Folder 32-50)
    Reel 4971
  - Correspondence, May, 1979-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 1-40)
  - Correspondence, 1942-1971, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 2-11)
    Reel 293
  - Oversized Correspondence from Box 5, Mar., 1976-Feb., 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Business Records, 1952-1978; Series 3; Archival Resource Key; 5 Folders Box 6
  Business records include Gershoy's will, receipts for the delivery of artwork to museums, and loan and consignment receipts.
  Business records are on reel 4971.
  - Gershoy's will, 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Receipts for delivery of artwork, 1969-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Loan/consignment receipts, 1966-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Miscellaneous receipts, 1967-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 44-45)
- Notes, 1967-1970, undated; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; 4 Folders Boxes 6, 9
  Notes include lists of names, as well as autographs of Georgia O'Keeffe and Woodstock artists Lucile Blanch, Agnes Hart, Doris Lee, Nicholas Marsicano, Robert Plate, Amy G. Small, Miron Sokole, and Phoebe Towbin.
  Notes are on reel 4971.
  - Lists of names, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Autographs, 1970, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Miscellaneous notes, 1967-1968, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Miscellaneous notes, 1967-1968, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 19)
- Writings, 1970, undated; Series 5; Archival Resource Key; 2 Folders Box 6
  Writings consist of short essays by Gershoy, including "Fantasy and Humor in Sculpture," instructions on the use of plaster, and a proposed project for a program in ceramics. Writings by others include poems by Bonnie Grainger, a handwritten poem titled "Dirge Without Music" by Edna St. Vincent Millay, and an essay, "On the De-Humanization of Education," by Francis V. O'Connor.
  Writings are on reel 4971.
  - Writings by Gershoy, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Writings by others, 1970, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 50)
- Artwork, 1932-1978, undated; Series 6; Archival Resource Key; 1 Linear foot Boxes 6, 8-9, OV 10
  Art work consists of sketchbooks, drawings, and prints by Gershoy, and art work by others including Alfred Banner, Rosalind Barnett, Lucile Blanch, Petra Cabot, Betty Hamilton, and Florence Weinstein.
  Artwork is on reel 4971-4972, and 293.
  - Sketchbook 1, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Sketchbook 2, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Sketchbook 3, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Sketchbook 4, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Sketchbooks 5 and 6 (see also box 8), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Sketchbook 7, of Mexico, 1948; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Sketchbook 8, of Mexico, 1971?; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Sketchbook 9, of Mexico, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Sketchbook 10 (see also box 8), 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Drawings by Gershoy, 1932-1978, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 60-67)
  - Prints by Gershoy (see also box 8 and OV 10), 1948, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - Artwork by others (see also sol 8 for drawings by Rosalind Barnett), 1968-1976, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 6, Folder 69-71)
  - Artwork, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Artwork, Sketchbooks, 1941, 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 13-14)
  - Oversized Sketchbooks 5 and 6 from Box 6, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Oversized Sketchbook 10 from Box 6, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Oversized Prints by Gershoy from Box 6, 1948, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Oversized Artwork by Others from Box 6, 1968-1976, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Oversized Prints by Gershoy from Box 6, 1948, 1975; Archival Resource Key (Box OV 10)
- Printed Material, 1932-1983, undated; Series 7; Archival Resource Key; 19 Folders Boxes 7, 9
  Printed material includes clippings, exhibition announcements and catalogs for Gershoy and others, press releases, brochures, programs, and reproductions of art work.
  Printed materials are on reels 4972 and 293.
  - Clippings, 1952-1983, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 1-5)
  - Exhibition announcements and catalogs for Gershoy, 1939-1983, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 6-8)
  - Exhibition announcements and catalogs for others, 1932-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 9-12)
  - Press releases, 1970-1977; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Brochures, 1966-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Programs, 1968-1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Reproductions of artwork, greeting cards designed by Gershoy, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Reproductions of artwork by others, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous printed material, 1971-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Printed material, news clippings, 1940-1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Photographs, 1916-1983, undated; Series 8; Archival Resource Key; 12 Folders Boxes 7, 9
  Photographs are of Gershoy, her Art Students League class with A. Stirling Calder, her friends, including Harry Gottlieb, Reuben Nakian, Joseph Pollet, Concetta Scaravaglione, Jean Varda, and her friends at Yaddo. There are also photographs of a studio interior, street views of Woodstock, New York, and art work by Gershoy and others.
  Photographs are on reels 4972 and 293.
  - Eugenie Gershoy (with friends), 1916-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Photographs of Gershoy's friends, 1940-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 20-23)
  - Photograph of a studio interior, 1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Photographs of Woodstock, New York, 1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Photographs of artwork by Gershoy, 1970-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Photographs of artwork by others, 1970-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Photographs, 1970-1971, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 16-18)